André Rodrigues

Phone: +44 730 797 6632; Address: 42 Captains Place, Southampton, SO14 3TE; E-mail: andrefgr@protonmail.com; LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/andrefgr

Seeking a position as a GRADUATE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Professional Profile Summary

Innovative programmer, motivated, focused, passionate and problem solver. Known to be organized, competent and good team worker. Even though I have no work experience, academic works have improved my skills, given me good programming practices, taught me to improve myself because I can always do better.

Education

Lisbon Superior Engineering Institute (ISEL), Portugal Bachelor's Degree in Computer and Multimedia Engineering 2014 – 2019

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: Java (including JSP, Java Servlets), JavaScript, PHP, HTML/CSS/Bootstrap, XML, C/C++, C#, AJAX, JSON, jQuery, Arduino, Python, Android, UML:

Databases: SQL, MySQL;

Web Server: Apache HTTP Server, Apache Tomcat;

Tools: Eclipse, IntelliJ Idea, NetBeans, Microsoft Visual Studio, Packet Tracer, Wireshark,

Adobe Premier, Blender, MS Office Suite; **Operating System:** Windows, Linux;

Academic Projects

"Home Manager" (Smart Home) | Final Project

- This project allowed me to understand how it is designed and implemented a computer system with Internet access, which collects and maintains sensory information concerning a household environment from a heterogeneous array of sensors.
- And how to create a middleware software to do the messages exchange between modules and the application. Communication between the modules was made through Wi-Fi and Bluetooth.
- Enable to explore the emerging IoT technology to make available to users a simple way to supervise their own home environment. The project was implemented in C/C++ (Arduino language), HTML/CSS, JavaScript and Firebase (Google database). For hardware we used Arduino boards, NodeMCU and a set of sensors.

"Best Gaming Events" (Content Management System) | Internet Multimedia Systems

- Analyse the technologies that support Content Management Systems, with emphasis on multimedia content systems;
- I learned to understand the most common development infrastructures, know how to use platforms for interactive content presentation, designing World Wide Web applications with multimedia content and how to use external services (Web Services) in the development of new features of a Content Management System;
- I also learned and reviewed several concepts with this project, such as: Windows and UNIX/LINUX operating systems, World Wide Web Apache server, PHP and Java Object Oriented Programming (OOP) and languages and the MySQL database system.

"Sport Shop" (E-Commerce) | Database Systems

- Consolidate design and implementation aspects of relational databases;
- I increased my knowledge of Structured Query Language (SQL) and Java Database Connectivity (JDBC) to create, alter or to question databases using Java Server Pages (JSP) in the context of the World Wide Web (WWW).

Employment History

Warehouse Operative at PFS, Southampton

11/2019 - 01/2020

- Manage pick ticket orders and pack them as necessary;
- Ensure that orders are accurate;
- Ensure warehouse goals are met:
- Load delivery vehicles;
- Perform other general warehouse duties as needed.

Postman at CTT – Correios de Portugal, Lisbon (Portugal) 04/2018 – 10/2019

- Capable and confident working in tight deadlines;
- Execute all tasks with the utmost rigor, increasing the efficiency of my section;
- Demonstrate flexibility by performing other functions and therefore improving productivity;
- Be able to teach and supervise new co-worker.

Languages

Portuguese: Native.English: Intermediate.